I think at meditation number 18 page
eight okay we're going to start the the
meditations and the lamrim book are
starting going to start to touch on the
refuge vows so these twelve vows and
this is the kind of the first one that
directly addresses that and it does mean
once you take refuge in the Buddha jewel
let me read you the vow
don't seek refuge in worldly objects and
deities after you have taken refuge in
the Buddha so anybody here who has a
Buddhist name you took this bow okay
already and it's nice to understand
about deke more deep so I I spend a lot
of time thinking about this now and I in
my feelings in the modern world there
are different religions you know there
are Buddhism Christians Jews Hindus
Muslims you know there are lots of
different religions and they have
different teachings my Christian says
that God took six days to make them
world and then on the seventh day took a
rest and that's why we should go to
church on Sunday something like that the
old religion of Tibet
burn assess that
the world was created by a monkey who
got had sex with a witch or something
like that okay something like that
and every religion has a different idea
where the world came from and who's
running the world okay but it seems to
me in my how I see things how I see the
world and I travel a lot so I get to see
many countries and I see them once a
year twice a year it's like I see
there's almost no place where we don't
go you know we just got invited to
Africa and I think we'll go because
itself South Africa so I kind of see
what people believe in and what they all
believe in is science is cell phones and
to be honest you know I think the
religion or the belief of this world is
it's not phones you know and it's shared
by all in all when you call it religion
I mean like Muslim people believe in
cell phones Christian people believe in
cell phones Jewish people believe in
stuff phones and you know if your cell
phone breaks and you you give the
personal choice you can you can pray to
Mohammed or you can pray to Yahweh or
you could pray to God or you can take it
to the cell phone fixing store they will
choose the cell phone fixing store
[Music]
we don't go to the church or the
synagogue and pray that the cellphone
will work you see and they don't try to
fix someone else's stuff oh okay
I've taught seed - I had a children's
group for many years it was my fourth
power for the for the mistake I made
with an abortion so for 15 years I
taught a children's group and one day in
New York we were I don't know if you
remember it was at Leon's place and I
was teaching this kids group and the air
conditioner broke and it was really hot
New York wet New York hot summer day and
and me and this other teacher we got up
on a ladder and we were trying to fix
the air conditioner and the kids were
running around and going crazy and then
this little boy came and grabbed my
pants legs and he pulled it you know he
said no no Gus to Michael you know don't
do that I'm like just be quiet I'm
trying to fix it no no you're not
thinking
I think I just you know go play I'm
trying to fiction he said you should go
outside find another person who air
conditioned is broken and how can fix it
that's the engine so everybody believes
in engines and motors and the internet
and computers and that's the real
religion of the world we have our
culture our parents you know get lit a
menorah on what Friday nights or our
parents
through painting each other on Diwali or
dressed up on what's that called
put him young I was in Tel Aviv in Yaffa
I'm for him which is a religious
Halloween and everybody was dressed up
as a angels and I was so happy you know
and I had to give a talk at the office
see it everything 800 people and I got
out of that car in my robes and some guy
arrives at mrs. cool mother for you even
look just like them that's a nice
costume
so we have our religious culture
Christmas dinner or you know Christmas G
Christmas songs but but what people
really believe in is science everybody
you know believes deeply and a big part
of their life is their cell phone what's
this called you ready
they left their cellphone in the taxicab
and then people go crazy people groan
like it's like they someone just told
them to have cancer you know so people
don't even so for me what we have to
compete with is not other religions like
I don't think this vow first of all
first refuge well I encourage you don't
think oh I'm not Hindu we don't like
Hindus I'm not Muslim we don't like
Muslims you know don't don't it like
that okay what we don't like is selfless
I think what we're competing with is
cell phones okay
people believe the cell phone works
because of Wang Shao and her friends but
people him distinct she's a manager for
Apple in in Shanghai you know we believe
that the cell phone works because these
people in Fox come they put the pieces
in the plastic and that's why it works
and we'll be done and and that's the
religion we are competing with okay
that's the one which is wrong okay why
does suffer work what would the boy say
in my kids class you have someone else
communicate you see you have two other
people communicate then your cell phone
will never break you got it okay what's
the Karma for the cover breaking I don't
know
you have to figure it out not being
clear to people okay so this meditation
at number 18 it's to try to recognize
inside of you you your real religion is
self or you know or car or airplane you
know and you believe that okay you
believe the way to get from Singapore to
LA San Francisco San Francisco is to get
on a plane you believe done and you
believe that the plane works if it has
all its metal parts you believe done you
know you don't understand that how you
got from Singapore to San Francisco was
that you helped other people get to
where they want to go otherwise the
flight would be canceled or they would
pull you off the plane if it was United
something like that
and it's very hard because we're
surrounded by seven billion people who
believe in science and you have to
struggle with it so in this meditation
and you can think about anything how
you're going to call your family when
you when you get home how you're going
to get home on an airplane or in a car
and you have to think about what makes
the airplane work and what makes the car
work or what makes the cell phone work
okay and if you can't overcome your
belief in the religion of science then
then you will never reach enlightenment
it's not possible okay I don't mean you
should hate your cell phone you should
love your cell phone you know I love my
cell phone and I use it for good things
and bad things too but you know they're
very valuable they're very precious they
are unbelievably cool but understand
where it comes from
okay and that's taking refuge when you
understand what really makes a cell
phone work when you think about it you
are taking refuge and then that taking
refuge helps to destroy your old Bad
Seeds it creates new good seeds your
life becomes magical everything we try
is successful
okay you love other people okay so this
meditation is the most important one he
said that about four other words okay
[Laughter]